本字幕由✿花語&花丸字幕組✿共同製作
QQ群：108244612
ヨナ姫 そろそろ出発しましょう
Princess Yona, we must depart.
冷えるね ここは
It's cold here.
山沿いですから
It does border the mountains.
あの頃は私 城の外がこんなに寒いって事 知らなかった
Back then, I had no idea it was so cold outside the castle.
This is the Kingdom of Kouka,
and that was once my castle.
ここは高華王国 そして嘗ても私の城
緋龍城は当時 王の他には
At the time, the king lived in Hiryuu Castle with no male heir, nor any queen to bear him one.
世継ぎの王子も 世継ぎを産む妃もなく
ただ 齢十五の王女だけが 大切に育てられていた
Only his beloved fifteen-year-old daughter was raised there.
This is the tenth year since the death of my father, the former king Ju-nam.
我が父君 先王ジュウナムが崩御し 今年で十年
Episode 1:
The Princess Yona
Our Kingdom of Kouka is a small country surrounded by powerful nations
この高華王国は南北を強大な他国に挟まれ
数多の戦乱に巻き込まれた小国
to the north and south, involving us in many wars.
However, thankfully, the last ten years have passed with no significant battles,
姫様は
Where's the princess?
Apparently she's still getting ready.
それがまだお仕度中でして
I see... because he's coming today.
そうか 彼奴が来る日だしな
and to this day, we have enjoyed prosperity in this land.
She's such a child.
ガキか
My daughter, Yona, will soon be sixteen years old.
間もなく我が娘 ヨナも 十六となる
I pray that under the divine protection of Hiryuu, the king of old,
願わくば 古の緋龍王の加護により
皆の平安が永久に続かむこと
the peace in this country will last for all eternity!
Long live King Il!
よくお似合いですよ 姫様
You look wonderful, Princess.
Forgive me, but you should proceed to the courtyard soon.
あの そろそろ中庭の方に
No! This won't do.
駄目 何か違う
Hey, where's that chintz?
ね あの更紗どこにあったかしら
Father! What about the ceremony?
お父様 式典は
As you can see, it's over.
見ての通り 終わったよ
Oh, no. I'm sorry. I...
嘘 ごめんなさい 私...
Well, no matter. It was merely a formality.
まぁよい 何の道 形式的な物
You don't need to appear before the people.
お前が人前に出る必要はないさ
Um, Father, isn't there something odd about my hair?
ね 父上 私の髪 変じゃない
Of course not! Your beauty surpasses that of any jewel-
変じゃないとも ヨナの美しさはどんな宝石も敵わん...
Yes, my face does.
顔はね 私もそこそこ可愛く生まれたと思うわ
I believe I was born with quite a cute face.
But why is my hair so red and unruly?
でもね この髪 どうしてこう赤毛で癖毛なのかしら
Grr! It won't behave at all!
ムギー ちっとも纏まらない...纏まらない
That isn't true. Right, Hak?
そんな事ないだろう な ハク
Fr
ee
ze
Fr
ee
ze
Fr
ee
ze
Fr
ee
ze
Fr
ee
ze
Fr
ee
ze
Fr
ee
ze
Fr
ee
ze
Fr
ee
ze
Fr
ee
ze
Fr
ee
ze
Fr
ee
ze
Fr
ee
ze
Fr
ee
ze
Fr
ee
ze
Fr
ee
ze
Fr
ee
ze
Fr
ee
ze
Fr
ee
ze
Fr
ee
ze
Fr
ee
ze
Fr
ee
ze
Fr
ee
ze
Fr
ee
ze
Fr
ee
ze
Fr
ee
ze
Yes, King Il.
ええ イル陛下
Who would ever say that
the princess's hair looks strange?
姫様の御髪が変などと だれが申しましょうか
If anything isn't right,
敢えて申し上げるなら 脳みそが変ですね
it would be her brain.
Quiet, knave!
お黙り 下僕
Father, do something about this impertinent cretin!
父上 こいつ何とかして 態度でかすぎ
Now, now. Hak has been your friend since childhood.
まぁまぁ ハクはお前の幼馴染だろう
それに この城を守る五人の将軍の一人
Moreover, he's one of the five generals who protect this castle.
He is the Wind Tribe's-
風の部族を...
I don't care! If you need guards, pick someone more lovable!
そんなの知らない 護衛ならもっと可愛げのある人がいい
Speaking of lovable...
可愛いと言えば いいんですか 可愛くしとかなくて
shouldn't you be trying to look lovable yourself?
Huh?
It seems Lord Su-won has arrived.
お着きになられたようですよ スウォン様
Y-You should have told me sooner!
そっ それは早く言いなさい
Su-won? Is that why you were concerned about your hair?
スウォン？ だから髪を気にしていたのですか
But why now?
しかしなぜ今更
It must be that thing they call a "maiden heart."
乙女心って奴じゃないですか
姫様
Princess!
Su-won...
スウォン
Su-won!
Kind Su-won, who has been by my side since we were children...
小さい頃から いつも私の側に居て 優しかったスウォン
My cousin, three years my senior!
三つ年上の私の従兄弟
For the first time in so long, today I get to...
今日は久々にスウォンに...
Whoa, there.
...see him!
会えた
You're as energetic as ever, Princess Yona.
相変わらず元気ですね ヨナ姫
Why the rush?
どうしたんです 慌てて
I-I heard you had arrived,
so I came to meet you.
スっ スウォンが来たって言うから 出迎えてやったのよ
Pet
My, what a good girl.
偉い偉い
Pet
Y-You can stay for a while this time, can't you?
こっ 今回は暫らく居られるんでしょう
Of course. I came to celebrate
your birthday in a week.
勿論 一週間後のヨナの誕生日の為に来たんだから
Wow. You're going to be sixteen years old!
いや ヨナは十六になるんですよね
Pet
You really have grown!
大きくなったなぁ
Pet
So where are King Il and Hak?
え イル陛下とハクはどこです
I must say hello!
ご挨拶しなきゃ
He treats me like a child.
子供扱い*3
Like a child. Like a child!
And I perfumed my clothes with the finest incense all morning
今日は朝から極上の香を焚き染めて
最高級の美容液と化粧を施したのに
and applied only the highest quality lotions and makeup.
All gone to waste.
無駄使いですね
Be quiet!
お前は黙ってて
Stupid Su-won...
スウォンのバカ
Yona, what's wrong?
ヨナはどうしました
Go away!
あっちへ行って
I heard you haven't been eating lately.
最近食事もしてないって聞きました
King Il has been worried-
イル陛下もご心配を...
Quiet!
煩い
大丈夫 こうすれば他からは見えません
It's all right. This way, no one else will see.
もう 泣いてもいいんですよ
You can cry if you want to.
I haven't been able to sleep...
眠れないの ずっと
without Mother beside me.
母上が側に居ないから
Yes, I heard the queen passed away recently.
うん お妃様 亡くなられたばかりですからね
I know! I'll be your mother, Yona!
あっ そうだ 私がヨナの母上になります
First of all, you need to eat.
とりあえず食事はしなきゃ
お師匠様に貰った梨 あげます
I'll give you this pear my master gave me!
Growl
Rumble
お妃様がしていた様に 眠るまで手を握ってます
I'll hold your hand until you fall asleep, like the queen did.
If you shed tears, I'll wipe them away, so no one will see.
ヨナの涙が零れたら
だれかに見られない様に拭ってあげます
So please, smile tomorrow!
だから 明日は笑って
Dummy. My heart is beating so loudly,
バカね 心臓の音が煩くて 余計眠れないじゃない
it's even harder to fall asleep.
あなたは 私の特別な人
You're my most special person.
G-Good morning, Su-won!
お おはよう スウォン
I have some of our best sweets!
取って置きのお菓子があるのよ
Would you like... to...
一緒に...って
What's the matter, Yona?
どうした ヨナ
If you're looking for Lord Su-won,
he's with General Hak.
スウォン様でしたら ハク将軍と一緒に
ハク狡い
No fair, Hak!
How could you set me aside
and have fun with Su-won?
この私を差し置いてスウォンと遊ぶ何て
Now, now. They haven't seen one another in some time, you know.
まぁまぁ あの二人も久々に会ったんだし
さすがですね ハク
Well done, Hak.
You were magnificent yourself, Lord Su-won.
スウォン様こそ お見事です
Next time, I'll strike dead center as well.
次は私も 真ん中だ
I'm going to do archery with Su-won too!
私もスウォンと弓やる
No! You mustn't handle weapons!
ダメだダメだ武器など
I don't even want to let those two use them.
あの二人にだって持たせたくない位なのに
Then you do it!
じゃ父上やってよ
But I'd get hurt.
怪我しちゃうじゃないか
まぁ臆病 大体父上はね...
You coward! You know, you're just...
ヨナ
Yona!
Come down. I'll let you ride with me.
いらっしゃい 馬に乗せてあげます
Okay!
Su-won!
スウォン
Relax. We'll both hold on to you.
落ち着いて 二人で支えますから
But...
でも...
Hak is about to die under the weight of the princess.
姫様の重みで 間もなくハクは絶命
張り倒すわよ
I'll beat you down!
Don't worry. You love horses, don't you?
大丈夫 馬 好きでしょう
I do.
好きよ
I love you.
大好き
Entrust your body to me.
私に体を預けていなさい
His voice... His breath...
声が...息が...
When he was a child,
he was cute like a little girl.
子供の頃は女の子見たいに可愛かったのに
これは反則じゃない
Isn't this against the rules?
Huh?
I mean, you seem to be accustomed
to dealing with women.
あぁっいえ... スウォンって女性の扱い慣れてる感じ
I bet you bring lots of women into your mansion.
案外お屋敷では山ほど女性を連れ込んでたりして...
Gosh, what am I saying?
あらあら何言い出すの私は
まさか...
I'm right?!
Please! You're mistaken.
嫌だな 誤解ですよ
There have been a few discussions of engagements, but...
確かに縁談の話は幾つがありますが
Engagements?!
縁談？！
いや 別にまだ決まっった訳では
Oh, but nothing is decided yet.
Let's not talk about this, okay?
もう 止めません この話
ヨナに言っても仕方ないですし
There's no need to trouble you with such things.
He's treating me like a child again.
また子供扱い
I-I've had proposals too!
わっ...私にだって縁談くらいあるわ
What? From whom?
え 誰と
ハクとか
Hak, for one!
バカ 寄りによってハクの名前は出る何てバレバレの見栄を
Idiot! Of all the names to give him,
Hak makes it too obvious!
だって仕方ないじゃない
年の近い男何て此奴しか知らないもの
I can't help it! I don't know
any other men near my age!
だから思いっ切り不審な目で見るのは止めてそこの従者
So stop giving me that suspicious look, you servant!
Um, I meant...
あの...今
いいんじゃないかなぁ
I think that sounds nice.
Congratulations!
おめでとうございます
You're cruel!
酷い
You're too cruel, Su-won!
How could you believe that lie?!
あんまりよスウォン あんな嘘を信じる何て
You're the cruel one. You're also a nuisance.
酷いのはあんただ そして迷惑だ
Your marriage may not be a lie after all.
お前の結婚は嘘にならんかもしれんぞ
Huh?
It would only be natural for you
to be betrothed by now.
そろそろ婚約者が居ても おかしくはないだろう
いや
No...
嫌よ 私はスウォンが...
No! I want Su-won to-
スウォンはダメだ
You can't have Su-won!
Princess...
姫様
I won't let you dictate my love life! I'm-
父上に私の恋愛をとやかく言われたくないわ 私は...
Yona, I have always given you anything you desired.
ヨナ 私はこれまでお前が望む物は何でも与えてきたよ
Beautiful hair ornaments, earrings,
美しい簪に耳飾り
離宮に花の庭園
a royal villa and a flower garden...
I'd give you anything that isn't a weapon.
武器以外の物は何でも
しかしお前がどれだけ望んでも
スウォンを与える事だけは出来ない
But no matter how you wish it,
I can't give you Su-won.
お前は高華王国の王女
You are the princess of the Kingdom of Kouka.
お前の夫となる者は この国の王となる者なのだ
The man who marries you
will become the next king.
スウォンは父上の兄 ユホン叔伯父上の息子
Su-won is the son of your brother, Yu-hon.
He's of royal blood.
王家の血筋でしょう
True, but it is my duty and right
as king to choose my heir.
そうだな だが後継者は王である私が選ぶ
Why not him? Su-won is a fine man.
どうして スウォンは立派な人よ
You're a cowardly king who's too
afraid to touch a weapon.
父上は武器を恐れて触れもしない 臆病の王様じゃない
I am indeed a cowardly king.
確かに臆病な王だよ 私は
Your mother was captured and killed by insurgents.
お前の母は賊に襲われ殺された
Such dangers go hand in hand with being part of a king's family.
王の一族にはこの様な危険が付き纏う
That is why I have had no desire to take a new wife.
それ故 私は再び妻を娶る気になれなかったよ
Yona, you want Su-won to be happy, don't you?
ヨナ スウォンには幸せになって欲しいだろう
I don't understand.
分からない
I don't understand, Father.
分からないわ 父上
だってそれなら 私の夫となる人は不幸になってもいいの
Does that mean it's all right for the man I marry to meet with misfortune?
私は幸せになってはいけないの
Am I not allowed to be happy?
でもそうよね 例え父上は許しても
But it's true. Even if Father allowed it,
スウォンにとって私はずっと子供の頃のまんま
in Su-won's eyes, I'm still the same child I was back then.
Su-won and I were never meant to be.
ダメじゃない 最初からスウォンと私は...
Who's there?
だれ
Hak? It's you again, isn't it?
ハク またハクでしょう
Only you would do something so senseless.
そんな下らない事して
No. It can't be!
まさか...そんな
Your mother was captured and killed by insurgents.
お前の母は 賊に襲われ殺された
No!
いや
Help! Someone... Someone!
助けて だれか だれか
Su-won!
スウォン
ヨナ
Yona?
Su-won...
スウォン
I'm sorry. Did I frighten you?
すみません びっくりさせちゃいました
I didn't know it was you.
急に入って来るものだから
Yona?
ヨナ
A s-strange man came after me.
へ...変な人が私を...
There's no one there.
だれも居ませんよ
That can't be! I...
嘘 だって...
逃げたんだ
He ran away.
A castle guard would have said something.
城の衛兵なら 普通に声をかけるもの
Yona?
ヨナ
Was he targeting me? Because I'm the king's daughter?
私を狙った 私が王の娘だから
Yona.
ヨナ
It's all right. I'm here.
大丈夫 私が居ます
Su-won...
スウォン
ダメ 私 スウォンとは居られない
No. I can't be with you.
Why not?
どうして
Because...
だって
If you stay with me, you'll be in danger.
私と居ると 貴方まで危ない目に
If you'd rather be with Hak,
I'll take you to his quarters.
ハクの側がいいなら 彼の部屋が送ってあげますよ
He's your betrothed, isn't he?
だって 婚約者なんでしょう
That's not...
違う
You don't need to hide it.
隠さなくても
Hak would be angry if he knew the two of us were alone here.
ハクに怒られちゃいますね
こんな所に二人ってきりだ何て
いや スウォン 違うの
No... Su-won, that's not it.
You don't have to return my feelings. Still...
振り向いてくれなくてもいいから だから...
私はスウォンの事がずっと...
Su-won, I've always...
思っても いいでしょう
I can love you, can't I?
It looks like the rain's letting up.
雨が少し小降りになったみたいですよ
He ignored me?
無視...した
Let me walk you to your room. I'll call a guard.
部屋まで送ってあげます 護衛を付きましょう
ス スウォン 私...
S-Su-won, I...
I'm sorry. Please don't come close to me.
すみません 側に寄らないでください
勘違いしそうになる
I may make a mistake.
What?
That is, a moment ago, it sounded as if you were saying that you...
つまり...ですり さっきの流れたとまるで まるでヨナが私を...
And if that weren't a mistake?
勘違いじゃなかったら
If it weren't a mistake, would that upset you?
勘違いじゃなかったら スウォンは嫌？
I can't let this happen.
困ります
I can't let myself see you as a woman.
あなたが急に女性に見えて困ります
What was I until now, then?
今までは何だったのよ
Huh? Oh, well, a younger sister, perhaps?
え えいや えっと 妹みたいな...
知ってたわよ
I knew that!
R-Right.
はい
I'm sorry. I'm unfamiliar with things like this.
すみません どうも私はこの手の事に疎くて
Su-won is turning red.
スウォン 真っ赤だ
So you lied about your engagement?
嘘ね 縁談は
あれは そう言う話もあるって事で
I just meant that discussions
about it have occurred.
今はまだ
I'm not engaged yet.
Su-won, do you see me as a woman now?
スウォン 私 女性に見える
At least, I couldn't sleep holding
hands with you anymore.
少なくとも 手を握って一緒に眠る何て もう出来ません
My nerves would prevent me from sleeping.
緊張で目が冴えてしまう
Well, that's fine.
まぁ いいや
If you've given me even the slightest consideration,
スウォンが私の事 少しでも気にしてくれたら
that's enough for now.
今はそれだけでいい
Yona...
ヨナ
Father, I really love Su-won.
父上 私やっぱりスウォンが好き
I don't know anything about the kingdom or kings yet.
国とか王とかまだ分からない
でも父上 彼が居るだけで 私は最高に幸せなのよ
Still, Father, just being by his side
is my greatest happiness.
Five days later,
五日後
緋龍城では十六になる私の誕生祝いの宴が行われた
a banquet to celebrate my sixteenth birthday was held in Hiryuu Castle.
Princess, we wish you a happy birthday.
姫様 お誕生日 おめでとうございます
ありがとう
Thank you!
Sixteen years old.
十六か
ヨナも立派になったな
How my Yona has grown!
はい
Yes.
Yona!
ヨナ
Father, my hair still won't lay flat!
I wanted to wear it up today!
父上
やっぱり髪が跳ねるのよ 今日は結い上げたかったのに
ダメだ 髪の事しか頭にない
It's hopeless. All she thinks about is her hair.
スウォン
Su-won!
Yona!
ヨナ
陛下 宜しければ
Your Majesty, if you'd like...
ありがとう ミンス
Thank you, Min-su.
な 何か用
I-Is there something you need?
Give me your hand.
手を出して下さい
A hair ornament?
簪？
I'm sorry to bring you out here.
すみません こんな所で
I thought it would suit you, so I wanted to give it to you personally.
ヨナに似合うと思って 手渡したかったんです
My hair...
私の髪...
is red and unruly, and it won't behave at all.
癖毛で赤毛で ちっとも纏まらないのよ
This wouldn't look right on me.
私には似合わないわ
What?
But I love your hair, Yona.
私は好きですよ ヨナの髪
It's a beautiful red, like the sky at dawn.
綺麗な赤 暁の空の色です
How simple am I?
何て単純
Just like that, I suddenly love my own hair.
一瞬にして 自分の髪が愛おしくなるなんて
Hak?!
ハク
His Majesty is looking for you.
陛下が探してましたよ
そう 部屋で休んでると伝えておいて
Is he? Tell him I'm resting in my room.
まぁ こんな事だろうと思ってました
Well, I figured this is what was going on.
Huh?
I am sure you could persuade
the king, Lord Su-won.
スウォン様なら 陛下を説得出来るでしょう
You misunderstand, Hak.
誤解ですよ ハク
And would you stop speaking so formally?
それに 敬語 止めません
Just call me Su-won, like you used to.
昔みたいにスウォンって呼んでいいのに
I am well aware of my place.
身分は弁えてますから
More importantly, don't you sense something?
それより 何か感じませんか
I can't place it clearly, but something feels off,
はっきりとは言えないけど 妙な違和感
城に何か入り込んだ様な
like something has made its way into the castle.
Now that you mention it,
Yona said something similar.
そう言えば ヨナもそんな事を言っていました
何
What?
It may be wise to keep an eye on those entering and leaving today.
今日出入りする人間を見張った方がいいかもしれませんね
Understood. I will increase security in the courtyard.
了解 俺は庭の警備を固めます
スウォン様は姫の所へ
Please stay with the princess.
好きだと言った スウォンが私の髪を
Su-won said he loved my hair.
No matter how you wish it,
I cannot give you Su-won.
お前がどれだけ望んでも
スウォンを与える事だけは出来ない
I need to discuss it with Father once more.
やっぱりもう一度 父上にきちんと話そう
私はスウォンを忘れられない
I can't forget about Su-won.
I'm sure Father will understand.
父上もきっと分かってくれるわ
The door is...
入口が
How careless, not posting guards here.
衛兵も置かずに不用心ね
そう言えばどうして衛兵が一人も居ないの
Come to think of it, why are there no guards?
I didn't see a single one on my way here.
ここに来るまで一人も見なかった
Father?
父上
F-Father!
ち 父上
あ まだ起きていたのでうか
Oh, you were still awake,
Princess Yona?
ヨナ姫
S-Su-won... Quickly, call a doctor.
ス スウォン 早く医務官を
イル陛下はもう目を開けません
King Il will not wake again.
I killed him.
私が殺しました
It's too quiet.
やけに静かだ
General Hak!
ハク将軍
You must be tired from your patrol.
見回りご苦労様です
さすがミンス 気が利くな
As always, you're so considerate, Min-su.
But are you sure you shouldn't be with the princess?
でもいいんですか
ヨナ姫様の側にいて差し上げなくて
Oh, I couldn't interfere.
姫さんにはスウォン様がついてるからな
The princess is with Lord Su-won.
では ついに姫様のお心がスウォン様に
Then, the princess's feelings have finally reached Lord Su-won?
さぁな でも時間の問題だろう
Who knows? But I'm sure it's a matter of time.
ハク様はお二人の事をよくご存知ですものね
You know the two of them well, don't you?
I've been watching them for a long time.
見てたからな 昔から
I just... Well, how should I put it?
あの二人には まぁ なんっつか
I want them both to be happy.
幸せになって欲しいと思ってる
お覚悟 姫様
Prepare yourself, Princess.
This is all for the sake of the Kingdom of Kouka.
これも高華國のためなんです
I've loved no one but Su-won since we were children.
幼い頃からずっと...ずっとスウォン だけだったのに
Su-won!
スウォン
これは一体どう言う事ですか
What is the meaning of this...
Lord Su-won?
スウォン 様
wakaru kai
Do you see
muriyari demo sakuhin de tsutaetokitai koto wo
What I'm trying so hard to convey through my work?
mukashi to kawaranai daro
It's always been this way, hasn't it?
yomizurai kashi mo haikei mo
The same obscure lyrics and background
sasaeru da to ga erasou ni sa
I've always talked ideals
nando mo nando mo itta kedo
Like supporting others
kotoba no karusa omoishiru no wa
I hope you don't realize too early
hayasuginai you ni
How irresponsible I was being with my words
yuki ga tsumetai wake nante
There's a reason why the snow is so cold
boku no te ga hito yori atsui kara
Since my hands are warmer than others'
kimi no sono te wo tsunaida toki
When I hold your hand
atatakai wo hikidasu tame
I'll be able to bring out the warmth in you
Next Time
スウォン
Su-won...
how did I appear in your eyes, my beloved?
愛おしいあなたの瞳に私はどう映っていたの
次回 暁のヨナ 第二話
Next time, Akatsuki no Yona, episode 2:
Episode 2:
Torn Bonds
ちぎれた絆
Torn Bonds.